The Guide to the Pittsburg, Shawmut & Northern Railroad Company papers, 1872-1960
Pittsburg Shawmut Northern Railroad Company, 1872-1960
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Pittsburg, Shawmut & Northern Railroad Company papers, 1872-1960
2161
C.F.H. Allen, 1895-
2.5 cubic ft.
Letters, pamphlets, broadsides, maps, newspapers, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Allen's history of the railroad, with research notes and correspondence; a corporate history. Railroad material includes correspondence, reports, financial records, employee records, timetables, pamphlets, newspapers, broadsides, maps, blueprints, charts, and photographs. Also records of predecessor, affiliated, or otherwise connected railroads.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Allen's history of the railroad, with research notes and correspondence; a corporate history. Railroad material includes correspondence, reports, financial records, employee records, timetables, pamphlets, newspapers, broadsides, maps, blueprints, charts, and photographs. Also records of predecessor, affiliated, or otherwise connected railroads.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Allen, C. F. H. (Charles Francis Hitchcock), 1895-, collector.; Pittsburg, Shawmut and Northern Railroad Company.
Subjects:
Railroads--United States.; Railroads--Employees.; Railroads--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Blueprints.; Broadsides.; Maps.; Photographs.; Timetables.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
- Timetables
  - Original timetable printed on red cardboard of the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad Co. effective June 15, 1896. This is an oversize file.
  - Photocopy of the Buffalo and Susquehanna Railroad Co. effective June 15, 1896.
- Loose-leaf notebooks, A count of all the photographs and material other than actual text in these volumes follows. THESE PHOTOGRAPHS AND OTHER MATERIAL MUST BE COUNTED EACH TIME ANY OF THESE VOLUMES IS REMOVED FROM THE STACKS AND RECOUNTED BEFORE THEY ARE RETURNED TO THE STACKS (see note signed by E.M.F. in box with books).
  1. Contains material relating to the predecessor roads and subsequent affiliated roads to the Pittsburg, Shawmut & Northern Railroad; incl. 156 pp. typescript of text by Mr. Allen and other items as noted below.
  2. Contains a complete history of the Pittsburg, Shawmut & Northern R.R. itself. pp. 157-254 + illustrations, etc. as noted below.
  3. Contains clippings and miscellaneous railroad ephemera - passes, etc. pp. 255-265 + unnumbered pp. of photos, etc. Additions, KJ, 5/62.
  - Book No. 1, Frontispiece - 2 photostats: 4 passes (on one sheet) to travel on various lines (issued to different individuals); map of Allegany County, N.Y. (1929) showing railroad lines.
    - Between pp.: 13 & 14 2 photos (1949) New York & Pennsylvania old roadbed near Swains (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 29 & 30 1 photo, Allegany Central #4 at Bolivar (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 35 & 36 1 photostat - map showing Rail lines in western New York State (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 42 & 43 2 pp. (3 photos) Piers of old bridge over Genesee River, Lackawanna & Pittsburgh RR. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 49 & 50 1 photo - The "Cannonball", Rochester, Hornellsville & Lackawanna # 34 engine and crew (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 56 & 57 1 photo - Engine #201 (no other identification) (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 57 & 58 2 photos - Lackawanna & Pittsburgh engines #308, 310 that were transferred to Central Railway of New Brunswick. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Between pp.: 58 & 59 1 photo - Engine #43 and crew (no other identification) (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 64 & 65 1 photostat - Letter dated December 21, 1889 to M.S. Blair from George Chapman re settlement of debt owed to U.S. Rolling Stock Co. by Lackawanna & Southwestern RR. Co. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 66 & 67 Photostat and original newspaper clipping of Lackawanna & Southwestern timetables for November 4, 1889 and June 24, 1890 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - pp. 86 Photostat - map of route of Clarion River Ry. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 91 & 92 2 photos: "A mixed train near Arrozo August 1941"; "C.R.#17 formerly T.V. [Tionesta Valley] #17 at Carman 1941 " (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 92 & 93 2 photos: (one is slight enlargement of the other) engine #2 2-4-4T Baldwin 1892 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 93 & 94 1 photo - Engine #119 4-6-0 (Clarion River Ry.) (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 94 & 95 3 photos - Engine House at Hallton, Pa.; C. R. Caboose #108; C.R. #55 at Carman (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 95 & 96 2 photos - Engine #19 of T.V. [Tionesta Valley] Ry. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 96 & 97 1 photo - "Caboose and a car of Acetic acid" (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 98 & 99 1 photo - "The Doodle Bug" (truck fitted with train wheels) (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - p. 99 1 photo - #55 at Hallton (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 100 & 101 1 photostat - Map of route of Mt. Jewett and Smethport RR (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 106 & 107 1 photo - Of Mitchell S. Blair (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 129 & 130 1 photo - "Filling trestle #51 (the famous horseshoe) at Swains, 1898 " (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 130 & 131 1 photo - "Horseshoe at Swains, 1945 " (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 132 & 133 1 photo - "Hornell to Nunda train Engine #12" (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 135 & 136 1 photo - "Trestle ready to be filled" (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 137 &138 1 photo "Stony Brook Bridge, winter 1899 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 1 photostat - Central N.Y. & Western RR. timetable #17, April 24, 1899 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 138 & 139 1 photo - Central N.Y. & W. Engine #32 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - Between pp.: p. 140 1 photo - Engine #26 (no other identification) (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 141 & 142 2 photos Hall & Kaul #70, First Engine Overhauled; Kaul & Hall #71 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 142 & 143 1 photo, Hall & Kaul Shay engines, St. Marys 1910 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 143 & 144 1 photo #7 St. Marys & South Western RR. (Box 1, Volume 1)
    - 148 & 149 2 photos #5 St. M. & S.W. RR.; # 11 St.M. & S.W. RR. (Box 1, Volume 1)
  - Book No. 2, Frontispiece (facing P. 157) - 1 photostat, map of The Pittsburg, Shawmut & Northern RR. route.
    - Between pp.: p. 160 1 photo - Shawmut line trestle crossing Penn. RR. track and Allegheny River (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 169 & 170 2 photos - North and south views of West Notch, P.S. & N. RR. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 176 & 177 1 photo - A work train on the P.S. & N. locomotive #1 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 1 photo - P.S. & N. engine #9 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 181 & 182 Map of P.S. & N. section of Main Line showing Palmerville Loop (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 182 & 183 4 photos: Kasson Loop before grown up (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Rear end of freight train on the loop, 10/12/42 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - A double-headed freight northbound engine #51-74 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Northern, lower end of loop in Oct. 1942 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 183 & 184 1 photo - "An excursion train at the loop" (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 1 photostat advertising excursion to St. Marys for the Shawmut opening (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 184 & 185 1 photo - "First train into Smethport 1902 #13" (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 185 & 186 1 photo - "Building the new bridge at Stony Brook" (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 186 & 187 5 photos: Test train crossing new bridge at Stony Brook (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - New bridge (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Both old and new bridges (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - New bridge in 1946 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Close up of new bridge (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Between pp.: 187 & 188 1 photo - Unidentified (probably of Stony Brook bridge) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 189 & 190 10 photos: The Y bridge at Olean over Haskell brook about 1908 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Same as above, 1945 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Track to Prosser (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Passenger train at Olean (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Old style switch (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Bridge over Angelica Creek at County House (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - South of County House (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Unidentified bridge (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Bridge over Genesee River at Belvidere (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Unidentified low bridge (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 192 & 193 1 photo - Shawmut engine #3 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 193 & 194 2 photos - Engine #8 on a train (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #9 at Olean (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 195 & 196 22 photos: Engine #12, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #13 on train (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Wreck (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Enlargement of derailed train #15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Second #15, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #17 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Builder's photo, engine #15 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Builders photo, engine #16 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #20, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Electric headlight, Ray Lacy in cab (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #22, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #23, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #41 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #43 with first coal train arriving in Brookville (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #41 and caboose at Brookville, Pa. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 196 & 197 Letter, dated Oct. 8, 1942, signed P.B. McBride granting Dr. Allen permission to photograph locomotives (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 197 & 198 29 photos: Engine #51 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #50 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #51 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #52 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #53 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #55 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #58 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #59, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #60 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #61 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #62 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #63 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #67 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #68 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #69 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #70 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #68 with electric headlight (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #70 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - A Shawmut caboose at Olean (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #71 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #72 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #73 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #74 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #75 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #76 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #98 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #98 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #81 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - p. 198 1 photo - Engine #119, Buffalo & Susquehanna, used on P.S.&N. in 1905 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 198 & 199 2 photos -- gas-electric #91; Unidentified crane on flat car (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 205 & 206 2 photos -- shipment of five new engines nos. 62, 63, 64, 65, 66; telegraph crew, 1918, old wooden box car showing big letters (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 206 & 207 5 photos: Car #291 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Passenger car open end #277 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Combination car #290 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Business car #299 "Janelyn" at Olean (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #99 private car of Frank Sullivan Smith (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 210 & 211 27 photos: Smethport, Pa. station (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Olean station (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - P.S. & N. station at Angelica (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - First, wooden station (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - After the fire (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Brick station and old handcar (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - After abandonment (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Little Genesee (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Birdsall (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Station at Friendship, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Station at Belvidere (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Factory on the Shawmut (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Coaling facilities at Angelica, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Car shop at Angelica, engines nos. 61, 63 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Car shop yard engines #15, 16 or 17 & 14 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Car shop at Angelica, engine #40 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Shawmut boxcars by shops, engine of the #40-[UNK] series (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Water tank at Angelica (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Angelica shops after abandonment (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Angelica shops before and after fire, May 15, 1917, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - After Angelica shops fire, engines 56 and 20 or 21 burned, (2 photos) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #56 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Boilers from #1 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - p. 211 1 photo - Angelica office (9 people, all identified, in front) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 211 & 212 1 photo - Engine #58 after St. Marys engine house burned (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 212 & 213 1 photo - Frank Sullivan Smith (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 215 & 216 3 photos - "An early freight near Belvidere (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - At Bennett's, N. Y. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Locomotive #10 on train #7 southbound (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 216 & 217 2 photos - "Engine #71, Car #286 near Ceres (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Car #132" (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 217 & 218 2 photos - Engine #59 on train near Hornell (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #68 on train near Richburg (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 218 & 219 Telegram dated 10/6/12 from J.A.B. to B. Moulton re removal of calf being pastured on right of way (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 219 & 220 Photostat of last timetable before Angelica-Bolivar link completed. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Photostat of P.S.&N. timetable (probably June 1902 ) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Photostat of covers of three P.S.&N. timetables (Dec. 1903, Nov. 1906 and June 1935) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 221 & 222 3 photos - #69 on freight approaching Angelica (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - # 71 and local freight along Allegheny River (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - A freight on the Shawmut view from the North [UNK] (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 222 & 222a 1 photo - A freight on the Portville bridge, engine #71 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 222a & 223 3 photos -- cabooses; a wooden coal car; a gondola (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 231 & 232 2 photos - Engine #72 and Car #290 salvaging rails near St. Marys (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Near Weedsville (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Between pp.: 232 & 233 2 photos - Engine #71 salvaging rails, leaving for Olean with a load of scrap (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - At West Eldred (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 235 & 236 Photostat - map of portion of line with location of Nile Wreck indicated (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 238 & 239 6 photos: Nile Wreck, Sept. 22, 1912 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - What was left of #11. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #68 with #63 in back (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Tender of #68 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Tender of #11 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Scene of wreck (unidentified) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 239 & 240 7 photos: [Nile Wreck cont.] (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 3 photos of #68 and right of way (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Coach #107 was next to engine and casualties were in this car (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Engine #68 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 2 photos, interior of wrecked coach #107 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 4 pcs. Mss. - inspection certificates for #11, last one prior to accident, and withdrawal from service. (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 240 & 241 Train order #20 P.S.&N. for train #9 (Mar. 17, 1931) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 241 & 242 Train order #5 P.S.&N. for engines # 51 & 74 (Apr.4, [UNK] (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 10 photos: [Wreck at County House] (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 2 photos - #65 at left, #226 in ditch (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #226 at left and #65 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #226 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Crane #244 working on wreck (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #63 clearing up #41 at right (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 2 photos - clearing up #72 on work train (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #65 at Angelica after wreck (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - #226 at Angelica (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - (John L. Smith and Isaac B. Irwin in front of engine in above picture of #226) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Accident report of County House Wreck, (1 sheet) (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - Report of wreck; caboose jumped track and burned, (1 [UNK] (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - p. 248 1 photo, #71 picking up scrap after abandonment (Box 1, Volume 2)
    - 248 & 249 1 photo - Dismantling Stony Brook Bridge, 1948 (Box 1, Volume 2)
  - Book No. 3, frontispiece (preceding P. 255) - map of P.S. RR. and connections
    - Between pp.: 259 & 260 1 photo - P. & S. (Pittsburg & Shawmut) crossing over the highway and B. & O. near Brockway (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 265 2 photos - Engine #577 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 265 Text and page numbers end with this page. The balance of this book consists of photographs, railroad ephemera and letters. The following page numbers are, therefore, my own and serve only to locate the material listed. The pages bear no numbers or other means of identification. (The page numbers used indicate the number of the page following p. 265). (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 1 3 photos - Engine #206 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #214 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #202 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 2 3 photos - Engine #208 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #210 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #208 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 3 3 photos - Engine #573 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #226 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #228 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 4 2 photos - An early train (Shawmut RR. Station at West Kittanning, Pa.) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #104, Schenectady (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 5 3 photos - Engine #200 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #201 lettered Allegheny River Mining Co. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - Engine #202 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 6 2 photos - Train #17 (crew standing in front) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - N.Y.C. #1669 became P. &S. #102 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 7 2 photos - A caboose (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - P. & S. switch (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 8 1 photo - Viaduct at Brookville, Pa., P. & S. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 9 1 photo - P. & S. viaduct at Brookville, Pa. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 10 1 photo - Sugar Camp viaduct (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 11 1 photo - Mill Creek viaduct (north view) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 12 1 photo - Mill Creek viaduct (south view) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 13 1 photo - Viaduct at Sprankels Mills, Pa., P. & S. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 14 1 photo - Crossing the Allegheny river at Mahoning, Pa., P. & S. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 15 2 photo - Construction work at Mahoning by P.S.&N., now P. & S. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 16 1 photo - Mauk Tunnel, southend, P. & S. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 17 1 photo - Stock certificate for 3,992 shares P.S.&N. to A.G.McComb, July 1899, stock certificate for 125 shares P.S.&N. to Henry Marquand & Co., Dec. 1900. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 18 3 employees' passes issued to R. Soranson for year 1908 (nos. 107, 381, 946), P.S.&N. RR. Co. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 19 3 employees' passes issued to R. Soranson for year 1909 (nos. 96, 433, 729) P.S. & N. RR. Co. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 20 3 employees' passes: Central N.Y.&Western RR. Co. to E. C. Lapey (?) 1897; P. & S. RR. Co. to R. Soranson 1918 and 1919. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 21 1 employees' pass, P.S. & N. RR. Co. to R. Soranson, 1909 (for one trip only) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 22 P.S. & N. RR. Co. first timetable after Bolivar-Angelica linked Dec. 27, 1903. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 23 P.S. & N. RR. Co. timetable Nov. 25, 1906 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 24 P.S. & N. RR. Co. timetable, June 16, 1935 (last timetable of line); clipping from St. Mary's Daily Press, Dec. 24, 1947 re approval of fees awarded to Shawmut receivers and trustees, and legal counsel (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 25 P.S. & N. RR. Co. timetable #22 Dec. 15, 1940 (last timetable before Angelica-Bolivar linked) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 26 Page #287 of a record book indicating scrap salvage value of engine #2 (photostat of this sheet is in book #2 marked as P. 195 -- this was apparently the original P. 195) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 27 Letter dated April 27, 1912 to I. B. Irvin (foreman, Angelica Shops) from H. S. Wilgus (Engineer, Maintenance of way) re disposition of surplus boiler tubes (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 28 Letter dated May 7, 1912 to H. S. Wilgus from J.A.B. indicates no use in Shops for boiler tubes (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 29 Photostat of letter dated Jan. 28, 1919 to J. L. Smith (Sup't. Motive Power & Equipment) from (name illegible) re insurance on boilers damaged in Angelica Shops fire. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 30 Order dated April 30, 1912 signed J.A.B. for work train to load & distribute gravel (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 31 & 32 2 page letter dated June 18, 1912 to H. S. Wilgus from Tait & Tait (attorneys) re responsibility of railroad for maintaining all highway crossings in good condition. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 33 Letter dated July 2, 1912 to J.A. Benson, roadmaster, from H.S. Wilgus notifying roadmaster of letter from Tait & Tait re crossings (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 34 Letter dated July 13, 1912 to J. A. Benson from H.S. Wilgus asking about responsibility for large rock that cannot be extricated from car 4338; (also pencilled notes from Benson to Krebs and Krebs' reply) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 35 P.S.&N. RR. Co. Steam Shovel Report for July 25, 1912 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 36 Letter dated August 26, 1912 from H. S. Wilgus to J. A. Benson re fences from Canaseraga to Hornell knocked down by sideplow. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 37 Letter dated August 27, 1912 from Wilgus to Benson re faulty construction of sideplow (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 38 P.S.&N. RR. Co. Daily Steam Shovel Report, Sept. 9, 1912 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 39 P.S. & N. RR. Co. gravel loading resume, Nov. 22, 1911-Oct. 8, 1912 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 40 Message dated Nov. 11, 1912 to Benson asking for advice as steam shovel is burying itself in quicksand - initialed W.W.N. (?) (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 41 Photocopy of letter dated April 23, 1915 from B.C. Mulhern P.S.&N. General Superintendent) to I.B. Irvin (General Foreman) re payment to W.P. Cannon for services performed during last half of March (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 42 Photocopy of letter dated June 9, 1919 from Frank Sullivan Smith (receiver) to I.B. Irvin (General Foreman, Angelica Shops) asking for specific reasons for resignation of several of the shop's employees. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 43 Letter dated Oct. 8, 1942 from F.H. Wells (general freight and passenger agent) to C.F.H. Allen re permission to photograph locomotives (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 44 Letter dated Oct. 30, 1942 from F. E. Berg (Sup't. Motive Power & Equip.) to C.F.H. Allen referring Allen to W.W. Robinson of Batavia for information and supplying some information about specific cars & engines. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 45 & 46 Two page letter dated Nov. 5, 1943 from F.H. Wells to C.F.H. Allen - answers to specific questions re P.S. & N. developement (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 47 Letter dated May 27, 1947 from Thomas C. Buchanan (trustee of P.S.&N.) to C.F.H. Allen - reply to letter asking for map of line, corporate history and annual reports. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 48 Letter dated June 13, 1947 from Thomas C. Buchanan to C.F.H. Allen -- reply to request for information. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 48 & 49 Letter and sheet of information dated April 4, 1944 from Allen G. Geertz (fuel engineer) to C.F.H. Allen re information about specific engines (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 50 - 61 Newspaper clippings from several papers (1939-1945) covering coal mining operations of P.S. & N. and the subsequent labor and financial difficulties leading to the road going into receivership (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 62 Personal letter dated Dec. 20, 1945 from Soranson to Allen re information about mismanagement of road by former officials (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 63 - 70 Typescript copies of newspaper articles from the Pittsburgh Post-Gazette and the Pittsburgh Press Sept.-Dec. 1945 supplied to Allen by Soranson (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 71 Letter dated Jan. 23, 1946 from Soranson to Allen (and three newspaper clippings) concerning period of coal miners' strike and appointment of new management for the line. (Box 1, Volume 3)
    - p. 72 - 92 Series of 21 letters from Soranson to Allen (and newspaper clippings) Jan. 23, 1946-Dec. 7, 1947 concerning post receivership period of the P.S.&N. (Box 1, Volume 3)